# Kumudha Narasimhan Software Engineering Manager

➤ kumudhakn@gmail.com

• United Kingdom

& kumudhan.github.io/

in in/kumudha-narasimhan

#### **SUMMARY**

10+ years of domain experience in optimizing applications across diverse architectures, complemented by a proven ability to align engineering initiatives with strategic business objectives. Demonstrated success in directing multiple large teams and cultivating well-supported, motivated, and high-performing environments that consistently deliver measurable results.

#### **SKILLS**

**Performance-Tuned Libraries** oneDNN, oneMKL, ONNX

Runtime

Application and libraries cuBLAS, cuDNN, CUTLASS, llama.cpp

Programming Language

C++, SYCL, CUDA, Python

Social

Agile methodologies, non-violent communication, mentoring / coaching, process design and audit, onboarding, mental health / neurodiversity awareness.

EU projects managed

AERO (open cloud acceleration), SYCLOPS (Al acceleration)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Jan 2023 – Present Edinburgh, UK

# Software Engineering Manager

Codeplay Software (Intel Subsidiary)

- *Managed 4 specialized Agile teams* working on: optimizing *llama.cpp* for Intel GPUs, developing a SYCL backend for CUTLASS, creating a hardware portable backend for oneDNN, and optimizing SYCL for CPUs. Defined and maintained roadmaps, tracked deliverables, and ensured timely execution across these teams and 2 EU projects, aligning efforts with broader division priorities.
- *Drove goal-setting and progress transparency* by coordinating division wide OKR reporting, maintaining company workboards, and implementing change requests based on evolving team needs.
- Provided *people-focused leadership* to 18+ engineers through regular 1:1s, feedback, performance reviews, onboarding support, and handling HR related issues across internal transitions.
- Collaborated across functions (HR, Agile coaches, infrastructure, leadership) to support team health, improve internal processes, enable team learning, and guide organizational initiatives.

Nov 2020 – Dec 2022 Edinburgh, UK

# Senior Staff Engineer

Codeplay Software

- *Led SYCL integration efforts* for projects like ONNX Runtime and implemented features in libraries such as portBLAS, portDNN and portFFT to optimize performance on heterogeneous hardware.
- Co-authored and contributed to several peer-reviewed publications (PMAM 2022, TACO 2023, P3HPC 2022) by driving technical content, managing review/rebuttal processes, and presenting results at major conferences and client demos.
- Improved engineering workflows and technical processes by establishing CI
  pipelines, improving reproducibility, defining merge request review protocols, and
  supporting ISO audit readiness through systematic best practices.

Sep 2019 – Nov 2020 Edinburgh, UK

# **Staff Software Engineer**

Codeplay Software

- Contributed to adding cuBLAS and cuDNN backends into oneMKL and oneDNN to enable GPU acceleration portability for these libraries. Collaborated with compiler teams to develop SYCL features to enable SYCL as a backend for ONNX Runtime.
- Optimized neural network inference on custom hardware for real-time performance as part of a customer-facing project.
- Published research on deep learning performance optimization in top-tier venues (ICS 2021, P3HPC 2020) - tile size selection model and cross- platform DNN portability.
- Presented SYCL tutorials and major events, including IWOCL 2021 and Intel Dev Summit 2021.

Jul 2018 – Jul 2019 Bengaluru, India

## Senior Software Engineer

Samsung Research India

- Analyzed *custom profilers and debuggers* for Samsung Tizen native and web applications, enhancing their functionality based on IoT team requests.
- Investigated and resolved issues reported in the Tizen Studio IDE to improve developer experience.
- Coached colleagues for the professional-level internal competitive coding exam, focusing on data structures and algorithms.

Jun 2012 – Jul 2015 Bengaluru, India

## Technology Analyst at Investment Banking Division

Goldman Sachs

- Building and standardizing frameworks in C# .NET and Java for all applications developed within the division with *focus on scalability and performance*.
- Inherited several C# projects and led their sustenance, ongoing development, and enhancements, including re-architecting the resource discovery system, entitlement system, and provisioning system.
- Communicated effectively with internal and business stakeholders, inducted and mentored new joiners, and resolved multiple critical issues within deadlines while managing expectations.

## **EDUCATION**

2018

Masters (by research), High Performance Computing & Compilers

Bangalore, India

Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore, India (Advisor: Prof. Uday Reddy)

- Thesis: Optimizing dense matrix computations with PolyMage
- A practical tile size selection model for affine loop nests [ISC 2021]

• Optimized geometric multigrid computations using a DSL approach [SC 2017]

2012

Bangalore, India

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science and Engineering

M S Ramaiah Institute of Technology